A Guide to the Papers of Harry Flood Byrd, Jr., 1813 (1936-1994) 1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Political Papers
  - Political Papers of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. Chiefly During His Service as a Virginia State Senator
    - Frederick County Legislation re Deer Hunting License 1950 (Box 44)
    - Gray Commission Report 1955-1956 (Box 44)
    - Gray Commission Report - News clippings & Printed 1954-1956 (Box 44)
    - Highway Tax Recommendation for Session 1964 1963-1964 (Box 45)
    - Highways 1958-1960 (Box 45)
    - Industrial Development 1962-1963, 1965, 5 folders (Box 45)
    - Industrial Development - Economic Data for Appomattox County through James City County 1964 (Box 45)
    - Industrial Development - Economic Data for King George County through Rappahannock County 1964 (Box 46)
    - Industrial Development - Economic Data for Richmond through Tazwell County 1964 (Box 46)
    - Industrial Development - Joseph Hamrick 1962-1964 (Box 46)
    - Industrial Development & Planning Advisory Board 1962-1964, 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Industrial Development - Printed Material ca. 1962-1965 (Box 46)
    - Industrial Development - "Report to the Governor of North Carolina from the Committee to Study Financing for Industrial Development" 1962 Nov 1 (Box 47)
    - Industrial Development Review in Richmond Times Dispatch 1964 Apr 5 (Box 47)
    - Interposition, Doctrine of 1955-1956 (Box 47)
    - Legislative Session - 1948, 1947-1948 (Box 47)
    - Legislative Session - 1949, 1949 (Box 47)
    - Legislative Session - 1950, 1950 (Box 47)
    - Legislative Session - 1952, 1951-1952, 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Legislative Session - 1952 Special Session on Redistricting 1950-1952 (Box 47)
    - Legislative Session - 1954 1954 (Box 48)
    - Legislative Session - 1955 Special Session on Segregation 1955 (Box 48)
    - Legislative Session - 1956 1955-1956 (Box 48)
    - Legislative Session - 1956 Special Session on Segregation 1956 (Box 48)
    - Legislative Session - 1958, 1956-1958 (Box 48)
    - Legislative Session - 1960, 1957-1960, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Legislative Session - 1962, 1960-1962 (Box 48)
    - Legislative Session - 1962 Tax Study Committee Report on General Sales Taxation & News clippings 1961-1962 (Box 48)
    - Legislative Session - 1962 Tax Study Committee Report on Revenue Patterns of Virginia State and Local Governments 1961 Oct (Box 48)
    - Legislative Session - 1963 Special Session on Poll Tax Amendment 1963 Nov (Box 49)
    - Legislative Session - 1964, 1961-1964, 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Legislative Session - 1964 Special Session on Redistricting 1964-1965 (Box 49)
    - Legislative Session - 1965 Special Session on Redistricting 1965 (Box 49)
    - Legislative Session - 1966, 1964-1966 (Box 49)
    - Local Government - Report on Comparative Costs 1947 (Box 49)
    - "Next Campaign" File ca. 1949-1965, n.d. (Box 49)
    - Outdoor Recreation Commission 1964-1965 (Box 50)
    - Outdoor Recreation Commission Report 1965 Jun 14 (Box 50)
    - Political Advertising - Cargill, Wilson & Acree, Inc. 1969-1970 (Box 50)
    - Political Surveys - Oliver Quayle and Company 1967, 1972-1974 (Box 50)
    - Poll Tax Resolution 1950-1953 (Box 50)
    - Redistricting 1961-1964 (Box 50)
    - Sales Tax 1948-1965 (Box 50)
    - Sales Tax - News clippings 1948-1965 (Box 50)
    - School Board Bill introduced by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1949 Nov 15-Dec 15 (Box 50)
    - School Board Bill introduced by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1949 Dec 16-1954, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - School Board Bill introduced by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - News clippings 1949-1952 (Box 51)
    - School Data 1958-1960 (Box 51)
    - School Distribution Formula ca. 1960-1962 (Box 51)
    - School Policy Study Commission, Mosby G. Perrow, Chairman ca. 1958-1959 (Box 51)
    - School Policy Study Commission, Mosby G. Perrow, Chairman - News clippings 1959 Feb 5-Apr 24 (Box 51)
    - School Policy Study Commission, Mosby G. Perrow, Chairman - Report 1959 Mar 16-31 (Box 51)
    - Speeches of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. ca. 1941-1969, 7 folders (Box 52)
    - Speeches of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - News clippings 1947-1957 (Box 52)
    - Tax Commission Study 1949 (Box 52)
    - Tax Problems in Virginia 1948-1950 (Box 52)
    - Tax Reduction Bill 1950-1953, 4 folders (Box 53)
    - Tax Reduction Bill - News clippings 1950-1954 (Box 53)
    - Tax Reduction Law 1953-1956 (Box 53)
    - U.S. Senate Staff of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Edwin B. Haakinson 1968-1969 (Box 53)
    - U.S. Senate Staff of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Jack Lewis 1968-1969 (Box 53)
    - U.S. Senate Staff of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - J. Philip Reberger 1973-1977 (Box 53)
    - U.S. Senate Staff of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Forrest Rettgers 1967-1969 (Box 53)
    - U.S. Senate Staff of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Forrest Rettgers 1970-1973 (Box 54)
    - U.S. Senate Staff of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Bill Utz 1968-1970 (Box 54)
    - U.S. Senate Staff of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. - Jack White II 1972-1973 (Box 54)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council 1957 (Box 54)
    - Virginia 350th Anniversary Commission - The 1957 Jamestown Festival 1953-1957 (Box 54)
    - Votes 1954 Session 1954 (Box 54)
    - Winchester, Political Papers re ca. 1946-1961, n.d., 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Workmen's Compensation 1958 (Box 54)
  - Files on Political Personages & Organizations
    - Watkins M. Abbitt 1953-1965 (Box 54)
    - J. Lindsay Almond, Jr. - Addresses 1952-1962, n.d. (Box 54)
    - J. Lindsay Almond, Jr. - Correspondence 1949-1961 (Box 54)
    - J. Lindsay Almond, Jr. - News clippings 1950-1964, n.d., 2 folders (Box 55)
    - T. Coleman Andrews, Sr. 1961-1962, n.d. (Box 55)
    - Remmie L. Arnold 1948-1949 (Box 55)
    - Arthur W. Arundel 1965 (Box 55)
    - John S. Battle - Campaign 1948-1949, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - John S. Battle - Campaign -Seventh District 1949 (Box 55)
    - John S. Battle - Correspondence 1948-1962, n.d. (Box 55)
    - John S. Battle - Speeches & News clippings 1948-1960, n.d. (Box 55)
    - William C. Battle 1960-1965, n.d. (Box 55)
    - Edward L. Breeden, Jr. 1961-1964 (Box 55)
    - Stuart E. Brown, Jr. 1960-1961, n.d. (Box 55)
    - Robert Y. Button 1961-1965 (Box 56)
    - Richard D. Chumney 1964 (Box 56)
    - Clark County Democratic Committee 1953-1956 (Box 56)
    - George M. Cochran 1961 (Box 56)
    - Lewis Preston Collins 1950-1952 (Box 56)
    - E.R. Combs 1946-1955 (Box 56)
    - Ted Dalton 1952-1957, n.d. (Box 56)
    - Colgate Darden 1945-1965 (Box 56)
    - Sidney C. Day 1959-1965 (Box 56)
    - Democratic Party of Virginia 1932-1963, n.d. (Box 56)
    - Democratic Primary Race for the 7th District Seat U.S. Congressional Race 1962 (Box 56)
    - Jesse W. Dillon 1963-1964 (Box 56)
    - John A.K.Donovan 1960 (Box 57)
    - Horace H. Edwards 1946-1953, n.d. (Box 56)
    - Election Laws of Virginia 1945-1962 (Box 56)
    - Elections - General ca. 1944-1971, n.d. (Box 57)
    - Charles R. Fenwick 1948-1961, n.d. (Box 57)
    - Frederick County Democratic Committee ca. 1953-1961 (Box 57)
    - J. Vaughan Gary 1950 (Box 57)
    - William Conrad Gibbons 1962 (Box 57)
    - Mills E. Godwin, Jr. - Correspondence 1960-1965, n.d. (Box 57)
    - Mills E. Godwin, Jr. - News clippings 1959-1965, n.d. (Box 57)
    - Fred T. Gray 1961 (Box 57)
    - Edward E. Haddock 1963-1964 (Box 57)
    - Porter Hardy, Jr. 1950, 1960-1964 (Box 57)
    - Albertis Sydney Harrison, Jr. - Campaign 1961, 4 folders (Box 57)
    - Albertis Sydney Harrison, Jr. - Correspondence 1957-1958, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Albertis Sydney Harrison, Jr. - News clippings 1958-1965, n.d., 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Albertis Sydney Harrison, Jr. - Speeches 1962-1964 (Box 58)
    - Burr P. Harrison - Campaign - Winchester 1948, n.d. (Box 58)
    - Burr P. Harrison - Correspondence 1942-1965, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Burr P. Harrison - News clippings & Printed 1947-1960 (Box 58)
    - Burr P. Harrison - Speeches & Statements 1948-1961, n/d/ (Box 59)
    - Burr P. Harrison - Votes 1947-1955, 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Garland Harwood 1964 (Box 59)
    - Horace Henderson 1962-1963 (Box 59)
    - Judge Walter E. Hoffman 1957 (Box 59)
    - George Humphrey 1957 (Box 59)
    - Martin A. Hutchinson 1946-1952 (Box 59)
    - Pat Jennings 1959-1965, n.d. (Box 59)
    - Lyndon Baines Johnson 1961 (Box 59)
    - Sidney S. Kellam 1953, 1960-1965 (Box 59)
    - L.M. Kuhn 1958-1965, n.d. (Box 59)
    - Sloan Kuykendall 1943 (Box 59)
    - Ben D. Lacy 1957-1965 (Box 59)
    - Bolling Lambeth 1952, n.d. (Box 59)
    - Loudoun County Democratic Committee 1963-1965 (Box 59)
    - Carter O. Lowance 1954-1965 (Box 59)
    - John O. Marsh, Jr. 1962-1965 (Box 60)
    - Richard A. May 1964 (Box 60)
    - Francis Pickens Miller 1952 (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous Political Speeches ca. 1948-1964 (Box 60)
    - E. Blackburn Moore 1956-1965 (Box 60)
    - C.H. Morrissett 1950-1965 (Box 60)
    - Richard M. Nixon 1954 (Box 60)
    - T. Nelson Parker n.d. (Box 60)
    - Mosby G. Perrow 1960 (Box 60)
    - Richard H. Poff 1962 (Box 60)
    - Fred G. Pollard 1965, n.d. (Box 60)
    - Nick Prillaman 1949 (Box 60)
    - Lacey E. Putney 1961 (Box 60)
    - A. Willis Robertson - Correspondence 1946-1964, n.d. (Box 60)
    - A. Willis Robertson - Statements & Speeches 1947-1958, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - A. Willis Robertson - Statements & Speeches 1959-1965, n.d. (Box 61)
    - A. Willis Robertson - Votes 1947-1955 (Box 61)
    - J. Kenneth Robinson 1962-1965 (Box 61)
    - Shenandoah County Democratic Committee 1946-1963 (Box 61)
    - Howard W. Smith 1960-1965, n.d. (Box 61)
    - Thomas B. Stanley - Campaign for Governor 1952-1953, n.d. (Box 61)
    - Thomas B. Stanley - Correspondence 1953-1962, n.d. (Box 61)
    - Abram P. Staples 1942 (Box 61)
    - A.E.S. Stephens - Correspondence 1953-1961 (Box 61)
    - A.E.S. Stephens - News clippings 1954-1963, n.d. (Box 61)
    - Kathryn Stone 1955 (Box 61)
    - James M. Thomson II 1957-1965, n.d. (Box 62)
    - Paul Trible ca. 1970-1982 (Box 62)
    - William M. Tuck - Correspondence 1945-1965, 3 folders (Box 62)
    - William M. Tuck - Speeches 1946-1953 (Box 62)
    - Lewis H. Vaden 1961-1964 (Box 62)
    - Dr. Louise Wensel 1958 (Box 62)
    - John H. Wessells 1962 (Box 62)
    - Winchester Democratic Committee 1947-1965 (Box 62)
    - Peyton B. Winfree 1958-1959 (Box 62)
    - John D. Wise 1950 (Box 62)
    - J.F. Wysor 1953-1954 (Box 62)
    - Edward E. Willey 1959-1961 (Box 62)
    - Elmo Zumwalt 1965, 1976, 1982 (Box 62)
- Miscellaneous Items
  - Plaques Awarded to Harry F. Byrd, Jr.
    - American Friends of Lubavitch "Celebration Eighty" honoring Rabbi Menachem M. Schneerson expressing gratitude and appreciation to United States government and Representative U.S. Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1981 Apr 8 (Box 63)
    - George Mason University Alumni Association Seventh Annual Alumni Awards Banquet - two mounted first day covers honoring George Mason 1982 May 22 (Box 63)
    - "Honorary Fire Chief" Friendship Fire Company 1774, Alexandria, Virginia 1983 Feb 21 (Box 63)
    - In Appreciation Harry F. Byrd, Jr. Speaker Odd Fellow and Rebekah Banquet 1988 Aug 27 (Box 63)
    - Shenandoah College and Conservatory "With Deep Appreciation for Leadership in the 1986-1988 $10 Million Campaign for Shenandoah" [1988] (Box 63)
    - Certificate of Appreciation for Support of 200th Anniversary Celebration Bicentennial Committee Gerrardstown Men's Club 1987 Oct 3 (Box 63)
    - Boy Scouts of America Leadership Member 1987 (Box 63)
    - Shenandoah University Board of Trustees In Appreciation of Exemplary Trustee Service 1994 Oct 5 (Box 63)
    - C. Irvine Cather Award from the Stonewall District Ruritan club 1995 (Box 63)
    - Fostoria engraved ashtrays with the U.S. Senate insignia and autograph of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. given as a gift from the Senator n.d. (Box 63)
    - Two cuts, featuring the Cardinal bird n.d. (Box 63)
    - Nameplates for [Senate?] Door n.d. (Box 63)
  - Political Cartoons
    - "Round One" by Anderson n.d. (Oversize T-14;1)
    - "Changing of the Guard" by Brooks in The Birmingham News 1965 Nov 30 (Oversize T-14:1)
    - "The Watch Byrd" by MacNelly n.d. (Oversize T-14:1)
    - "Yes, Santa Claus, There Is a Virginia" by Joe Parrish in The Chicago Tribune 1953 (Oversize T-14:1)
    - "And Now the Barrel" by Art Wood in The Richmond News Leader 1954 Feb 8 (Oversize T-14:1)
    - "The Egg and You and I" by Fred Seibel (re income tax reductions) 1950 Mar 4 (Oversize 1950 Jan-Jun)
    - "The Shooting Star" (re Senator A. Willis Robertson) 1952 Nov 9 (Oversize 1952 Jul-Dec)
    - "Woodman, Spare That Tree!" (re the Byrd automatic Tax Reduction Law) 1954 Feb 5 (Oversize 1954 Jan-Jun)
    - "Byrd Tax Credit Law Tussle" 1954 Feb 11 (Oversize 1954 Jan-Jun)
    - "Look Who Got the Ax!" (re the Carter Bill) 1954 Feb 22 (Oversize 1954 Jan-Jun)
    - "Read All About It" (re the Announcement by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. that he will not be a candidate for governor in 1961) 1960 Dec 14 (Oversize 1960 Jul-Dec)
  - Photographs & Other Items
    - Large drawing of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. by Douglas Brown 1938 (Oversize T-14:2)
    - Photograph of the Members of the Senate of Virginia by the Foster Studio, Richmond, Virginia, including Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1960 (Oversize T-14:2)
    - Two photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. in a car, taken at the funeral of his wife at the Episcopal Church, Winchester, Virginia n.d. (Oversize T-14:2)
    - Photograph of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. and another man with the caption "Secret Parley----Exposed!" n.d. (Oversize T-14:2)
    - Picture of the Supreme Court by Ernest L. Daly n.d. (Oversize T-14:2)
    - Certificate of Merit of the Lee Editorial Award, 1939, given to Harry F. Byrd, Jr. for a series of editorials advocating Equal Justice in the Courts 1940 (Oversize T-14:3)
    - Virginia Press Association Certificate of Award to The Winchester Evening Star 1958-1959, 3 certificates (Oversize T-14:3)
    - Virginia Press Association Certificate of Award to The Winchester Evening Star 1970-1972, 6 certificates (Oversize T-14:3)
    - O'Sullivan Corporation Resolution of Merit given to Harry F. Byrd, Jr. ca. 1995 (Oversize T-14:3)
    - Poster describing the "Object of Rotary" [International] n.d. (Oversize T-14:3)
    - Photograph of the Board of Directors of the Associated Press, including Arthur Sulzberger ( New York Times), Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Ben Mikelray ( The Washington Star), Paul Miller (President of Gannet Newspapers), Frank Starzel, Mark Ethridge ( Louisville Courier Journal), John S. Knight (President Knight Newspapers), Norman Chandler (Publisher Los Angeles Times), Roy Roberts (editor Kansas City Star), Robert McLean (Publisher Philadelphia Bulletin) 1950 (Oversize T-14:4)
    - Photograph of the signing of the Amended Byrd Tax Reduction Bill, including (left to right) Thomas Blenton, Robert O. Norris, Governor John S. Battle (seated), Edward Breeden and Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1952 Feb (Oversize T-14:4)
    - Photograph of Governor Lindsay Almond 1957 Nov 5 (Oversize T-14:4)
    - Photograph of President Lyndon B. Johnson being greeted by the board of Directors of the Associated Press at their Annual Meeting 1964 (Oversize T-14:4)
    - Photograph of Governor John S. Battle n.d. (Oversize T-14:4)
    - Presentation Folder containing a Color Photograph of President Lyndon B. Johnson giving his State of the Union Message before Congress 1967 Jan 10 (Oversize S-56)
    - Scrapbook of News clippings re the Democratic primary campaign of Senator Harry F. Byrd, Sr. for the U.S. Senate, against Francis Pickens Miller 1952 May-Jul (Oversize S-56)
    - Budget Sheet figures for 1960 Legislative Session ca. 1960 (Oversize S-56)
    - Political Advertisement Poster for Harry F. Byrd, Sr. addressed to the Veterans of Virginia 1946 (Oversize S-56)
    - Photographs of the Board of the Associated Press 1950, 1961-1963 (Oversize S-56:1)
    - Virginia Legislature Budget Sheets ca. 1960 (Oversize S-56:1)
    - Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. at the dedication of "Sully" as a Virginia Historic Landmark ca. 1966 (Oversize S-56:1)
    - Photograph of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. with Mills Godwin (autographed) 1974 Jan 12 (Oversize S-56:1)
    - Color Photograph of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. at the Young American Medals program in the Rose Garden 1981 (Oversize S-56:1)
    - Photograph of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. with Robert C. Byrd (autographed) n.d. (Oversize S-56:1)
    - 3 copies of a map of Virginia with its counties n.d. (Oversize S-56:1)
    - Photograph of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. at the Campaign Headquarters n.d. (Oversize S-56:1)
    - Color Photograph of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. with other Senators in a Committee Meeting n.d. (Oversize S-56:1)
    - 9 Photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. with Lyndon B. Johnson (two autographed) 1967-1968, n.d. (Oversize S-56:2)
    - Color Photgraphs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. with Richard Nixon 1973 May 19 (Oversize S-56:2)
    - Photograph of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. with Jerry Ford (autographed) n.d. (Oversize S-56:2)
    - Photograph of Hubert H. Humphrey (autographed) n.d. (Oversize S-56:2)
    - Blueprints Showing the Proposed Norfolk & Western Railway Company Siding for Harry F. Byrd, Charles Town, West Virginia 1945 Nov 6, 6 copies (Oversize 18)
    - Maps of Virginia showing the Population of Virginia Counties and Cities by House and Senatorial Districts, from Special Session on Redistricting 1952 Apr (Oversize 18)
    - Plat of H.F. Byrd Inc. Orchard Land in Jefferson County, West Virginia 1953 Aug (Oversize 18)
    - Plat of Two Parcels of Land, with improvements, property of H.F. Byrd Inc. in Berryville, Clarke County, Virginia 1953 Sep 26 (Oversize 18)
    - Award of Honorary Membership given to Harry F. Byrd, Jr. in the Friendship Veterans Fire Engine Association of Alexandria, Virginia 1990 Sep 29, Framed Item
    - Campaign Managers for the Democratic Primary 1966
    - Campaign Managers for the General Election 1966
    - Campaign Managers for the General Election 1970
    - Campaign Managers for the General Election 1976
    - A-Z Card File with the Names & Addresses of Supporters & Contributors by District ca. 1966-1981